Sagar Shah

□ 973-413-0750 | Sss6498@qmail.com | Asagarshah.me | Esagar-shah4

Summary.

Currently a Consumer Product Manager with three years of experience. Experience as both a Growth PM and pre-PMF PM at a fintech startup. Previously learned product as an APM at Capital One after graduating with a Computer Engineering degree from Rutgers. Organized collaborator with a drive for business and consumer impact through well-designed technology.

**Education** 

## **Rutgers University - Honors College**

NEW BRUNSWICK, NJ

B.S. COMPUTER ENGINEERING, MINORS: COMPUTER SCI., POLITICAL SCI., & CYBER SECURITY

SEPT 2016 - MAY 2020

• GPA: 3.52/4.00 | Presidential Scholar (Full Tuition and Housing) | Dean's List | IEEE Eta Kappa Nu Honors Society President

**Reforge** Remote

MASTERING PRODUCT MANAGEMENT

OCT 2022 - Nov 2022

Work Experience

Octane - Series D Startup; B2B2C Lending

REMOTE / NEW YORK, NY

PRODUCT MANAGER, CONSUMER

FEB 2022 - PRESENT

- Spearhead the product strategy, roadmap, and features for Octane Prequal, a digital retail financing tool
- Develop features to attain 90% dealer retention (up from 70%), enabling Sales to onboard 400 dealers in 2022 (10x growth)
- Optimize the consumer funnel by analyzing and remediating friction, increasing look-to-book by 25% year over year
- Validate product-market fit for a new retail product; subsequently launch to 100 dealers via a campaign with Marketing
  Re-architect back-end to deliver custom integrations 4x faster; identify opportunity and scope design with Engineering

• Re-architect back-end to deliver custom integrations 4x faster, identify opportunity and scope design with Engineering

ASSOCIATE PRODUCT MANAGER

AUG 2020 - FEB 2022

- Cut debit card processing costs by \$6.3M/year by developing a data stream of debit servicing data system of record
- Delivered on internal data teams' requirements that would enable real-time intelligent experiences for debit customers
- Collaborated with Tech, Design, Operations, Risk, and Legal to launch the first ATM refresh to consumers in over 3 years
- Designed and developed a real-time, empathetic, and engaging ATM customer experience with personalized messages
- Conceptualized and led scoping for an ATM Content Management System that shortens UI release times by 87%
- Analyzed ATM customer calls and launched a "Need Help?" screen (with ADA compliance) to address 68% of issues

Accenture New York, NY

**TECHNOLOGY CONSULTING ANALYST** 

JUNE 2019 - AUG 2019

- Analyzed and updated 47 QA SQL scripts for the cloud upgrade of client's revenue management system, following SDLC
- Consulted at a pharmaceutical firm, governing SharePoint, creating kickoff deck, and leading weekly client meetings

Merck & Co. Kenilworth, NJ

**EMERGING TECHNOLOGY BUSINESS ANALYST** 

JUNE 2018 - AUG 2018

- Increased users of the Innovation Room by 20+/week by redesigning the room with intuitive UX and building a kiosk app to showcase Merck's new technology; publicized improved room by hosting and leading demos of products and features
- Developed and monitored a SharePoint dashboard for an extensive digital transformation project in an Agile environment

## **Rutgers University Career Services**

NEW BRUNSWICK, NJ

DATA AND TECHNOLOGY ANALYST

JUNE 2017 - MAY 2019

- Provided technical support to resolve 50+ issues/week regarding Office 365, networks, printers, Web, Windows, and Mac
- Identified fraudulent employer trends with Tableau and recommended solution to eliminate 40% of student scams

**Projects** 

**AssetManager** 

PERSONAL FINANCE ANDROID APP

LITTLE FALLS, NJ JUNE 2020 - JULY 2020

- · A budgeting and data visualization app for a customer's checking, brokerage, retirement, and credit card accounts
- Implement Node. is and Express for a REST API web server, MongoDB for database, and Java for a front-end Android app

#### **Autonomous UAV Human Reconnaissance**

New Brunswick, NJ

SENIOR DESIGN PROJECT - Sixth Place out of 70 Teams

MAY 2020

Automate a drone using Machine Learning and Computer Vision to optimally search and rescue people after a disaster

### **Facial Recognition Home Security Automation**

NEW BRUNSWICK, NJ

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FINAL PROJECT

MAY 2019

• Work in team to create an IoT security system that disarms alarm at sight of recognized faces, configurable through an app

# Skills & Interests

**Languages** Python, Java, JavaScript, C, HTML, CSS, LaTeX, SQL, MATLAB **Frameworks:** Node.js, Express, Git, Bootstrap

Tools Tableau, Jira, Android Studio, MongoDB, AWS, Windows, Linux, MacOS, Office 365, Adobe Suite, CAD

**Interests** Travel, Photography, Cars, Lifting, Cooking, Podcasts, Theology, Tennis, Ping Pong, Chess